Finding Aid for Department of Chemical Engineering (University of Michigan), publications, 1916-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Department of Chemical Engineering (University of Michigan), publications 1916-2004 1969-1990
University of Michigan. Department of Chemical Engineering.
0.6 linear feet
9724; Bimu; C146; 2
The Department of Chemical Engineering publications include brochures and pamphlets, bulletins and course catalogs, histories such as the History of the Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan, Manuals entitled How to Succeed in Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan, and programs from the Donald L. Katz Lectureship in Chemical Engineering.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor No. 1884 ).
The publications is open without restriction.
BIOG/HIST
The Department of Chemical Engineering Publications (.6 linear feet) consists of three series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications and Topical Publications. The bulk of the publications document the Department of Chemical Engineering.
The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Department of Chemical Engineering. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
The Unit Publications series includes brochures, bulletins, directories, histories, manuals, and programs. The bulletins include course catalogs for the department from 1916 to 1940. There are also descriptions of the graduate program in Chemical Engineering from 1974 to 1995. There are two histories in the Unit Publications series. The first is a brief history written in 1980. The second, A Century of Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan..., published in 2002, was compiled by Professor James O. Wilkes as a centennial history for the department. How to Succeed in Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan was written to help incoming students find their way through the department, the university and the city of Ann Arbor. There are programs describing the Donald L. Katz Lectureship in Chemical Engineering from 1971 to 1989.
The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs and organizations within the Department of Chemical Engineering. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit. This series includes brochures from the Industrial Affiliates Program.
The Topical Publications series includes printed materials published to document specific events or activities such as fund-raising or one-time conferences hosted by the Department of Chemical Engineering. The Topical Publications materials document the Centennial celebration in 1998 including one newsletter entitled 100 Years.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Chemical Engineering.; Donald L. Katz Lectureship in Chemical Engineering.; Donald L. Katz Lectureship in Chemical Engineering.; History of chemical engineering at the University of Michigan.; How to succeed in chemical engineering at the University of Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Pamphlets.; Bulletins.; Histories.; Manuals.; Programs.
- Unit Publications
  - Brochures
    - General, 1960-1994 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Announcement of the Course in Chemical Engineering ..., 1916-1925, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Program in Chemical Engineering ..., 1926-1927 (Box 1)
    - Chemical Engineering, 1929-1934 (Box 1)
    - Courses in Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, 1935-1940 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Studies in Chemical Engineering, 1974-1995, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Directories, 1988 and undated (Box 1)
  - Histories
    - A Century of Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan: A Miscellany of Contributions From Historical Documents, Students, Alumni, Staff, Faculty, and Friends, 1898-2002, compiled by James O. Wilkes, 2002 (Box 1)
    - History of Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Digital Computing, FORTRAN IV, WATFIV, and MTS, by B. Carnahan and J.O. Wilkes, 1976 (Box 1)
    - How to Succeed in Chemical Engineering at the University of Michigan, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - Donald L. Katz Lectureship in Chemical Engineering, 1971-1989 (Box 1)
    - The Goff Smith Lectures, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Symposia held at the University of Michigan, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Visitation Committee, 1987 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Industrial Affiliates Program
    - Brochures, undated (Box 1)
- Topical Publications
  - Centennial Celebration
    - Newsletters
      - 100 Years, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Programs, 1998 (Box 1)